原创翻译：Circle did it for Joan
双语制作：dahongying@CHD
请送我去医院！
Please, get me to a hospital!
我不能呼吸
I can't breathe.
你知道吗？如果够聪明的话 现在最好不要说话
You know what? If you were smart, you would stop talking right now.
告我啊 我只知道 妇女不该为妇女工作
Sue me. I just know that women should never work for women.
你怎么能这么说？
How can you say that?
因为他们会感到威胁
Because they're always threatened.
特别是如果你比他们美丽
Especially if you're beautiful, and they're not.
很好！你从未与你的上司吵过架？
Fine! You never had a fight with your boss?
从来没有 你知道为什么吗？
Never. You know why?
因为他是一个男人
Because he's a man.
我们能不能换话题呢？
Can we please drop this?
我只是想回家 吻我的儿子 老公
I just want to go home and kiss my son. Honey.
你看 你非要提到你有一个孩子 而我们没有
See, you have to mention that you have a child and we don't.
- 那就是我的看法 - 艾瑞特 我没有那个意思
- There's my point. - Erit, I didn't say anything of the sort.
不要道歉 这是基因使然
Don't apologize, it's genetics.
女人总是互相竞争
Women are always competing with each other.
这就是为什么你和你的老板处不来
That's why you're having problems with your boss.
- 因为她是个女人 - 完全正确
- Because she's a woman. - Exactly.
妇女应为男人工作 男人为女人 就是这样
Women should work under men, men under women. That's it.
那男人为男人工作勒？
What about men under men?
这也很好   我的意思是 他们较能相处
That's fine, too. I mean, they can deal with it.
- 我们可以走了吗？ - 谁想再喝一杯吗？
- Can we go now? - Either of you guys want another drink?
- 我们还好 - 一杯？两杯？
- We're good. - Shot? Double?
妇女能成就令人惊叹的事情 像我就是
Women can do amazing things. I am one. I know.
但是 即使我都不愿当我的部下
But even I would never work for me.
这点我们有共识了 晚安 米克
That we can agree on. Good night, Mick.
我们处得很僵
We are in a bad mood.
她的话有道理 兄弟 你知道的
She's got a point, bro, you know.
我宁愿当你的下属而不是他的
I'd much rather work under you than her.
这很好 我也愿意在他手下工作
That's nice. I'd rather work under him, too.
你宁愿在约翰“底下”工作？
You'd rather "work" under John?
你连这个都不爽喔？
You have a problem with that, too?
不！为什么我会对你的小小性暗示不爽？
No! Why would I have a problem with your little sexual innuendo?
你今晚有啥毛病啊？
What is up your ass tonight?
那么 我应该呆坐在这里 看你就在我面前挑逗我的丈夫？
So I should just sit here while you come on to my husband right in front of me?
拉娜 如果我想要你的丈夫 我会拥有他 就像这样
Lara, if I wanted your husband, I would have him, like that.
像怎样？你还能给露更多的奶给他看？
How? You couldn't possibly show him more of those tits.
- 你知道你的问题是什么吗？ - 好啦
- You know what your problem is? - Okay...
我的问题是你的大脑跟这只鸡的一样大
My problem is your brain is as big as those tits.
- 宝贝 是你的错！ - 是 我的错！
- Baby, this is your fault! - Huge, exactly!
这是你的…
This is your...
如果你有它一半的大脑 我们就不会讨论这个问题
If you had half a brain, we wouldn't be having this conversation.
宝贝 随它去吧 随它去吧
Baby. Let it go, let it go, let it go.
- 晚安 亲爱的兄弟！ - 晚安！
- Good night, brother dear! - Good night!
- 她真的是目空一切 - 现在你信我了吧！
- She's completely full of herself. - Don't try and agree with me now!
我甚至怀疑她真的是一个专业牙医吗
I don't even think she's a member of the dental profession.
停止
Shut up!
她可能连“麻醉师”都不会拼
She probably can't even spell "anesthesiologist."
- 那个女人根本是个冒牌货 - 我们去过她的办公室聚会 你这白痴！
- The woman's a complete fraud. - We went to her office party, you idiot!
我相信 她那天晚上一定有偷打我
And I believe she hit on me that night as well.
你胡思乱想
You are completely delusional.
刚刚在里面她也没打你啊 我只是不喜欢她
She didn't even hit on you in there. I just don't like her.
我知道你的意思了 真的 我同意你
I understand your point of view. I really do. I agree with you.
像她那付德性根本不配帮人口腔手术
Somebody who looks like that should not be allowed anywhere near oral surgery.
你是个混蛋！
You are an asshole!
坐下来 保持冷静
You're sitting in the chair, you're trying to stay calm,
别再跟他们计较了…
and you got them things hanging in your face...
- 所以 下周见罗？ - 好的
- So, see you next weekend. All right? - Okay.
谢谢您！- 晚安
- Thank you. - Good night.
- 再见 - 再见
- Bye. - Bye!
再见
Bye!
哦 天啊
Oh, gee.
看看这个
Look at this.
- 现在你说冲 - 冲啊！
- Now you say go. - Go!
粉碎
Smash.
好了 过去点
All right, squeeze in.
你不能每天早上都这样做 太老土了
You know, you can't do this every morning. It's way too corny.
来吧 笑一个
Come on. Smile.
我只做到他18岁
It's just till he's 18.
- 一份礼物 - 哦 太棒了 这是什么？
- A present. - Oh, great. What's that?
你讨厌刷牙 用这个只要30秒
You hate brushing your teeth and that brushes them in 30 seconds.
我爱刷牙 不要相信你妈说的
I love brushing my teeth. Don't believe everything your mother says.
- 你最后一堂课几点？ - 三点
- What time's your last class? - 3:00.
但我有些考卷要改 你可以去接卢克吗？
But I got some papers to grade. Can you pick up Luke?
经过昨天的事 我可能已经失业了 所以…
After yesterday, I probably don't have a job anyway, so...
说她胸大无脑是我的错吗？
Was it wrong of me to call her a useless cow?
我认为是老板的都会欣赏那种坦诚的交流
I think bosses admire that kind of frank exchange.
- 打给你爸了吗？ - 什么时候？
- Did you call your dad? - When?
他生日 昨天！
Birthday, yesterday!
有啊 我送他一些新鲜的鲜花 粉红色的小玫瑰
Yeah, I sent him some freshly cut flowers, little pink roses.
还给他一张手工制作的卡片
I sent him a handmade card.
而我年初开始缝的被子已经完工了
And I finished that quilt I've been sewing since spring.
你真是多才多艺
You are completely impossible.
那你知道我今年的生日得到了啥呢？ 我得到了打呼声
Did you notice what I got for my birthday this year? I got a grunt.
妈妈说：“祝你生日快乐 亲爱的 ”而爸爸就…
Mom said, "Happy birthday, sweetheart," and Dad went...
这真是…这是一个我人生最美丽的时刻 我都哭了
It was just... It was a beautiful moment in my life. I teared up.
“胰岛素” 一家之主成熟点好吗？
Ever think that somebody has to be the bigger person here?
你要记住这事 以后作证
Now I want you to remember this for the custody hearing,
妈妈总是爱念爸爸 好吗？
how Mommy is always scolding Daddy, okay?
你会记得吗？
Can you remember that?
到老你就知道
You know, how are you gonna feel
卢克长大后 你的生日连通电话他都不打
when Luke grows up and doesn't call you on your birthday?
而现在她试图离间我们的感情
And now she's trying to drive a wedge between us.
- 好 我放弃 - 现在 她放弃你了
- I give up. - And now she's abandoning you.
嘿 哥们 你想试再击倒他一次？
Hey, buddy, do you wanna try and knock him over again?
准备好了吗？对准它
You ready? Line it up.
- 瞄准后喊冲 - 冲啊
- Line it up now and you say go. - Go!
我来开门
I got it.
匹兹堡警局 这是逮捕拉娜布伦南的拘票…
Pittsburgh Police. This is an arrest warrant for Lara Brennan...
- 逮捕？为了什么？ - 和房子的搜查令
- Arrest for what? - ...and a search warrant for the premises.
- 等一下 - 拉娜布伦南？
- Hold on! - Lara Brennan?
- 你再碰我 我就逮捕你 - 等一下
- You touch me again, I'm gonna arrest you. - Hold on.
- 你待在那里！ - 这是我的家！
- Stay where you are! - This is my house!
- 拉娜布伦南？  -我是
- Lara Brennan? - Yes!
我要逮捕你
I will arrest you.
你被指控谋杀了伊丽莎白 吉赛斯
You're under arrest for the murder of Elizabeth Gesas.
冷静！- 我的孩子还在厨房！
- Calm down! - I got my kid in the kitchen!
你在干什么？逮捕她是为了什么？
What are you doing? Arrest her for what?
- 转身 - 妈咪！
- Turn around! - Mommy!
- 约翰！约翰！ - 你有权请律师…
- John! John! - You have the right to an attorney...
照顾卢克 照顾卢克
Go get Luke. Go get Luke.
- 你有权利…… - 卢克！
- ...understand these rights... - Luke!
没关系 孩子！没关系！
It's okay, buddy! It's okay!
- 妈咪！ - 卢克！
- Mommy! - Luke!
不会有事的 没事的！
It's all right. It's okay!
爸爸！爸爸！
Daddy! Daddy!
- 爸爸！ - 怎么了？发生什么事 伙计？
- Daddy! - What's wrong? What's wrong, buddy?
发生什么事 ?
What's wrong?
我抱抱
I got you.
嗯 你可以睡这儿…
Well, you can stay in here
只要你睡在床的这一面 好吗？
as long as you sleep on this side of the bed, all right?
装哭? 狡猾…
You little snake.
我不知道为什么我一直被骗
I don't know why I keep falling for the same old trick.
你还挺有一手 不是吗？
You have your tricks, don't you?
嘿 快睡觉
Hey, go to sleep.
快快睡
Go to sleep.
- 但山姆是你的朋友 不是吗？ - 吃饭的时候不是
- But Sam is your friend, right? - Not at lunch.
- 为什么 难道他偷你的食物？ - 不是
- Why, does he steal your food? - No.
- 他说了关于妈妈的坏话？ - 是的
- Did he say something mean? About Mom? - Yeah.
- 你打他？  - 对
- Did you hit him? - Yeah.
好 你在哪里打他？
Good. Where'd you hit him?
在操场上
On the playground.
哇！那一定很痛“县立监狱”
Wow! That must have hurt.
站在别动 孩子
Hold it there, son.
只是个玩具
It's a toy.
感谢你
Thank you.
嘿 没事
Hey. All right.
另一只手臂
And the other arm.
不要担心车车 我们等下会拿回来
Don't worry about the car. We'll get it back later, okay?
嘿
Hey!
嗨 亲爱的！
Hi, honey!
嗨
Hey.
你不给妈咪一个吻？
You won't give Mommy a kiss?
可以亲妈咪一下吗？
Can Mommy please have a kiss?
讨厌鬼 给你妈妈一个吻
Rat-bag. Give your mom a kiss.
- 爸爸有念我的信给你听吗？ - 每天晚上睡觉前
- Is Daddy reading you my letters? - Every night at bedtime.
是吗?
Yeah?
你好香
You smell so good.
你打算盖什么呢？
What are you gonna build today?
你要盖一个堡垒？
You gonna build a fort?
大门吗？还是城堡？
A door? Or a castle?
嘿
Hey.
他害怕去上学？
Was he scared going to school?
不会 我陪着他一起走路上学 给了他一个吻 他就走进去
No. I walked him to his class, gave him a kiss, he just walked right in.
甚至没有回头挥个手
Didn't even turn back for a wave.
看看小朋友们！
Look at his friends!
是他的书桌
And his desk.
- 你的第一天如何？ - 非常好
- How was your first day? - Excellent.
只有一半学生睡着 你知道
Half the class stayed awake, you know.
- 我跟你妈谈过 - 她会来？
- I talked to your mom. - When is she coming?
她的生意有很多麻烦 所以…
She's having a lot of trouble with her business, so...
好吧 这才几年而已 她会处理好的
Well, it's only been a couple of years, I'm sure she'll get around to it.
有任何消息吗？
Have you heard anything?
关于上诉？
About the appeal?
有啊 我刚刚决定不告诉你
Yeah, and I've just decided not to tell you.
- 记得 迈尔说的 - 千万别划地自限
- Remember what Meyer said. - Don't.
可能需要几个月让法庭作出裁决
It can take months for a court to make a ruling.
我有看到那个女人 她在那里 她不可能就消失了
I saw that woman. She was there. She couldn't have just disappeared.
迈尔在寻求重起调查
Meyer is looking for a new investigator.
她的外套钩住我的皮包 我还听到钮扣掉了
Her coat snagged my purse, and I felt that button pop,
他们是瞎子 如果他们不能找到它
and they're blind if they can't find it.
他要再次检查过所有的证据
He's gonna go through all the evidence again.
那很好 因为我们还没有完全破产
That's great, because we're not quite bankrupt yet.
我们很好
We're fine.
无论你一再说谎哄我
How you just lie and lie.
你还是如此英俊
But you're so handsome.
你能帮我一个忙吗？
Can you do me a favor?
我不知道 我有点忙
I don't know, I'm kind of busy.
我要你去选州长
I need you to run for governor.
我能做到
I can do that.
你就可以更改牢里夫妻会面的规则了
You can change this rule about no conjugal visits,
因为我不认为我可以再撑 20年
'cause I don't think I can last another 20 years.
嘿
Hey.
我没事
I'm okay.
- 我没事 - 一切都会好转的
- I'm okay. - Everything is gonna be all right.
我保证
I promise.
你想他还会愿意吻我吗？
You think he'll ever kiss me again?
请你站起身来
I need you to stand up.
碰 捉到你了
Tag, you're it.
卢克！该走了 野猴子
Luke! Let's go, yard ape.
嘿
Hey.
- 好玩吗？  - 好玩
- Have fun? - Yeah.
她疯疯的 对不对 那个小女孩？
She's kind of crazy, that little girl, right?
该走了 嘉莉！
Time to go, Carrie!
不要！
No!
他甚至看都没看一眼
He didn't even read the thing.
不用多久 我告诉你…他会看的
Half the time, I'm telling you... We'll get him in there.
如果我们找到那个离开停车场的女人勒？
What happens if we find the woman who was leaving the parking lot?
法庭速记已经拒绝了
The PCRA has been rejected.
不可以提交新的证据 一个都不行
No new evidence can be submitted. Not anymore.
那是抢劫啦
It was a robbery.
如果嫌犯用过她的信用卡 我们就有论点了
And if they had used her credit card, we could have argued that.
我…我很抱歉
I'm... I'm sorry.
约翰…
John...
这真糟
This sucks.
好了 就是这样
Okay. That's that.
我们现在只能仰赖最高法院了 对不对？
All we have now is the Supreme Court, right?
约翰 在过去 30年来
John, in the last 30 years,
最高法院没有听审过任何谋杀案
the Supreme Court has not heard one murder case.
任何大律师都不会具件上诉
No decent lawyer would even file the pleadings.
所以 我所要做的就是找到一个“不那么伟大”的律师吗？
So, all I have to do is find an indecent one?
这应该不会太难
That shouldn't be too hard.
我会上诉
I'll file it.
但我需要你为我做一些事情
But I need you to do something for me.
什么事？
What?
我要你好好看看证据 忘记拉娜是你的妻子
I need you to look at the evidence and forget that Lara's your wife.
我看过证据 迈尔
I've seen the evidence, Meyer.
我不是在评断她无辜或有罪 我只说你去看证据
I'm not saying judge her innocent or guilty, I'm just saying look at it.
她的同事看到她离开现场
Her co-worker sees her leaving the scene,
在她的衣服有受害人的血液 凶器上都是她的指纹
the victim's blood is on her clothes, her fingerprints are on the murder weapon.
然后跟我们去吃晚饭？
And then we went out to dinner.
如果你刚刚杀了人你会这么做？
How do you do that if you just killed somebody?
那法官会认为她有精神病质
That would make her a psychopath.
- 还有争执… - 你说拉娜是精神病患？
- And the fight... - Is Lara a psychopath?
- 在办公室的争执呢 ？ - 每个人都会跟自己的老板吵架！
- The fight in the office? - Everyone fights with their boss!
但不会闹出人命啊
But this one ended up dead.
那你的意思是 你从来都不相信她是清白的？
So what you're saying is that you never believed in her innocence?
- 你怎么能这么说？ - 你要说什么 迈尔？
- How can you say that? - What are you saying, Meyer?
我是说 我们现在相信什么不重要了
I'm saying that it no longer matters what we believe,
拉娜是不可能逃得掉了！
Lara is not getting out!
你不知道我多不想这么说
And you have no idea how much I hate to say that.
我会找别人提上诉
I will find someone to file the pleadings.
约翰
John.
约翰 拜托 约翰！
John, come on. John!
约翰！
John!
约翰！看在老天份上！
John! For Christ's sakes!
别这样吧
Come on.
我们去跟狗狗玩 好吗？
We'll find Scout, okay?
感谢你
Thank you.
“给一个大拥抱给企鹅 小企鹅 琪琪和小袋鼠
"And give a big hug to Pengui, Little Pengui, Kiki and Opossumy.
很爱很爱你的 妈咪   “
"Lots and lots of love, Mommy."
我们要写回信吗？
Should we write her back?
我能拿个铜板吗？
Can I have a quarter?
你要拿个铜板？
Can you have a quarter?
可以啊 可是这些是不能花的喔
Yeah, but you know you can't spend these.
因为他们是从乡下小屋拿来的 我和妈妈常带你去…
Because they come from the cottage where Mom and I used to take you
当你还是个小婴儿时
when you were a baby.
那可以都给我吗？
Then can I have them all?
当然
Sure.
我的妻子 拉娜布伦南 她被送到了这里
My wife, Lara Brennan, she was sent up here.
- 布伦南 布-伦-南 - 我很抱歉 但她被禁客访
- Brennan, B-R-E-N-N-A-N. - I'm sorry, but she can't have visitors.
离谱 我要见她
That's ridiculous. I have to see her.
- 拉娜！拉娜！ - 我很抱歉
- Lara! Lara! - I'm sorry.
你不能去那里！
You can't go down there!
- 你不能进去！ - 嘿 嘿 站住 停在那儿
- You can't be in here! - Hey, hey, stop. Stop right there.
- 你要去哪？ 嘿 回来这里 - 拉娜！
- Where you going? Hey, come back here. - Lara!
- 拉娜！ - 先生！
- Lara! - Sir!
- 这到底是怎么回事？ - 我的妻子企图自杀
- What the hell is going on? - My wife attempted suicide.
他们把她带到了这里 我要去看她 拜托
They brought her up here. I have to see her, please.
- 她不允许访客 - 为什么她不是在急诊室？
- She's not allowed visitors. - So why isn't she in the ER?
- 因为她是县立监狱转来的 - 只用两分钟 拜托
- Because she's a transfer from County Jail. - Just two minutes, please.
两分钟
Two minutes.
好
Okay.
感谢你
Thank you.
两分钟
Two minutes.
因此 唐吉诃德的一生与他的时代
So, The Life and Times of Don Quixote.
它是怎样的呢？
What is it about?
信仰美德 比美德本身更重要？
That someone's belief in virtue is more important than virtue itself?
是的 当时的确是 但究竟说的是什么呢？
Yes, that's in there. But what is it about?
难道是说理性的思维会如何摧毁你的灵魂？
Could it be about how rational thought destroys your soul?
难道是谈非理性是如何强大 终将胜利？
Could it be about the triumph of irrationality and the power that's in that?
你知道 我们花了很多时间来组织世界
You know, we spend a lot of time trying to organize the world.
我们发明时钟和日历 我们甚至尝试预报天气
We build clocks and calendars and we try and predict the weather.
但是 我们的生活的哪一部分是真正的在我们的控制之下？
But what part of our life is truly under our control?
如果我们选择相信的纯粹只是自己想像的现实呢？
What if we choose to exist purely in a reality of our own making?
这是否会使我们疯狂？
Does that render us insane?
如果是这样 生命不就只是绝望？“越狱高手的自传”
And if it does, isn't that better than a life of despair?
这是一个课程 探讨驱使人不计代价追寻自由的原因
It's a course that investigates what drives men to be free, no matter the cost.
其他老师教小狗玩赏吗？
Some other teacher had dibs on Papillon?
你从监狱逃出七次
You escaped from jail seven times.
你想知道什么？
What do you want to know?
为什么只有你作得到 别人不行
How you escaped when no one else could.
胆子和一点点运气
Balls and a little luck.
世界上没有监狱是真的密不透风
No prison in the world is airtight.
每座监狱都有一把“钥匙” 看你如何找到它
Each one has a key. You just have to find it.
你怎么做到的呢？
How do you do that?
仔细观察
A lot of looking.
特别是那些不合常规的事
Especially at things that break up the daily routine.
守卫们每一逃诩习于做着同样的事情
Guards get comfortable doing the same thing day in, day out.
一旦意外发生 这时候他们就可能犯错
Something happens, that's when they make mistakes.
当你看到机会时 你必须做好准备
When you see it, you have to be ready.
你必须有着全面而周详的计划
You have to have the entire plan already in place,
甚至在你还不知道要如何逃狱前就计划
even before you know how you're going to get out ofjail.
逃逸是容易的 最难的是保持自由
Escaping is easy, the hardest part is staying free.
你要知道你要去哪里以及你如何能到达那里
You have to know where you're gonna go and how you're gonna get there.
你要知道他们打算如何抓住你 何时何地
You have to know how they plan to catch you, where and when.
那么 你到底是如何知道那些的？
Well, how the hell are you supposed to know that?
付钱给知道的人
You pay off someone who knows.
还有监狱是在乡下或城里也有关系
And a lot depends on if the prison is in the country or the city.
城里
City.
你从哪里来？
Where are you from?
匹兹堡
Pittsburgh.
匹兹堡监狱很难
Pittsburgh's tough.
他们有太多桥梁和隧道可以设点抓你
So many bridges and tunnels they can block off.
从他们开始打电话
From the time they make the call,
警方15分钟内就能封锁整个市中心
the police can have the center of the city sealed tight in 15 minutes.
他们啥时变得如此精实？
How can they be so exact?
911之后 国土安全局规定每一个城市都制定锁城计划
After 9/11, Homeland Security made every city have a lockdown plan.
匹兹堡 费城 波士顿 明尼波利斯 都是15分钟
Downtown Pittsburgh, Philly, Boston, Minneapolis, 15 minutes.
全城警戒
They can do D.C. in under 10.
35分钟内 每个州际收费站都会有警察站岗
Within 35 minutes, they can have cops at every tollbooth on the interstate
而且二级公路上开始交通管制
and be running rolling stops on the secondary roads.
他们还不会有你的照片 但他们会有你的描述
They won't have your photograph yet, but they will have your description.
如果走不掉呢？三十五分钟的时间不是很多
What if you can't get out? Thirty-five minutes is not a lot of time.
只好投降
Then surrender.
否则他们会当场击毙你 以及你的任何同伙
Because they will shoot you on sight, along with anyone else you're with.
远离火车和巴士站
Stay far away from the train and bus stations.
忘了当地机场 去另一州搭飞机
Forget the local airports. Leave from another state.
第二 身份证明 找到假证件很容易
Second, identity. It's easy to find fake papers,
找到能通机场关的 很难
harder to find ones that will get you through an airport.
你需要一本护照 驾驶执照和社会安全号码
You'll need a passport, a driver's license and a social security number.
如果你要租一辆车 找一个收现金支票的地方
If you have to rent a car, find a place that will take a cash deposit.
他们还是会做信用检查 因此要用真有其人的名字和证件
They'll still run a credit check, so use a real person's name on the ID.
第三 目的地
Third, destination.
找个不吸引美国游客的地方
You want somewhere that doesn't attract American tourists.
例如叶门之类的
Think Yemen, and you get the idea.
还有钱 你需要很多很多钱
And money, you'll need a truckload of it.
一切都很贵 酒店 旅游 资讯
Everything's expensive, hotels, travel, information.
要多少 ？
How much?
至少要够五 六年用
Enough to last at least five, six years.
你的钱用完了 你的朋友也用完了
You run out of money, you run out of friends.
但在你做任何事情之前 你要问自己 真能做到吗
But before you do anything, you have to ask yourself if you can do it.
你能不妄想再见到你的父母吗？
Can you forget about ever seeing your parents again?
你能杀死警卫？把你的孩子一个人留在加油站？
Can you kill a guard? Leave your kid at a gas station?
把某个无辜的老太太推到地上
Push some nice old lady to the ground
只因为她挡到你的逃生去路？
just because she gets between you and the door?
因为要做这件事情 你就要变成这种人
Because to do this thing, that's who you have to become.
如果你不能 就别蠢动
And if you can't, don't start,
因为你只会害别人死
'cause you'll just get someone killed.
你是怎么被抓的？
How did you get caught?
我自己投降了
I gave myself up.
我没法睡觉 因为一直担心有人破门而入
I couldn't take wondering when someone was gonna come through the bedroom door.
所以 你口袋里有多少？
So, what do you have in your pocket?
祝你好运
Good luck.
世界上没有监狱是真的密不透风的
No prison in the world is airtight.
每座监狱都有一把钥匙 看你如何找到它
Each one has a key. You just have to find it.
你怎么做到的呢？
How do you do that?
仔细观察
A lot of looking.
特别是那些不合常规的事
Especially at things that break up the daily routine.
在您左侧 是阿勒格尼县监狱 目前世界上最大的监狱
And on the left, the Allegheny County Jail, now the largestjail in the world.
发生过三次越狱 没有人活着离开
There have been three escape attempts of which no one has made it out alive.
如果你看看右边 是南侧…
If you look to the right, south side...
“在第一个楼梯间 这是个很小的楼梯转弯处
"On the first landing, which was as small as the necessary turn of the stairs allowed,
“柱子中有一个缝隙 大约半码宽
"there was a niche in the column, about half a yard wide,
“ 然而在此缝隙中 王子不禁认为 有一个人站在隐蔽处
"and in this niche, the prince felt convinced that a man stood concealed.
“他认为他可以分辨出有人站在那里”…
"He thought he could distinguish a figure standing there..."
25 26 27
25, 26, 27,
28 29 30
28, 29, 30.
良好
Good?
还有钱 你需要很多很多钱
And money, you'll need a truckload of it.
一切都很贵 酒店 旅游 资讯
Everything's expensive, hotels, travel, information.
我们选择好图片
It's gonna take our selection.
然后 我们要用到我们的魔术套索工具
Then we're gonna wanna use our magic lasso tool
来去除背景的门
to get the door out of the background.
嘿
Hey.
…身份证明 找到假证件很容易
Identity. It's easy to find fake papers,
找到能通机场关的 很难
harder to find ones that will get you through an airport.
- 奥施康定 - 10美元一片
- OxyContin. - $10 apiece.
五片算你 40美元
Give you five for $40.
嘿 我需要一些护照
Hey, I need some passports.
滚开！快给我走!
Piss off, man! Beat your feet.
好啦 伙计！
Okay, boy!
护照你必须先付款的哟
You got to pay upfront for the passports, yo.
- 我会先付钱 - 你知道拉斐特酒店？
- I can do that. - You know the Hotel Lafayette?
它在大街上 你到那里时 去酒吧 找哈维
It's on Main Street. When you get there, go to the bar, ask for Harv.
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
就说'老鼠'要你来的
Tell him Mouss sent you.
哈维在哪？我在找哈维
Harv? I'm looking for Harv.
- 你是哈维？ - 是的
- Are you Harv? - Yeah.
'老鼠'叫我来找你
Mouss told me to come and see you.
是吗？你想要什么？
He did, did he? What do you want?
三本护照 驾驶执照 和一个真的社会安全号码
Three passports, a driver's license, and a real social security number.
你怎么认识'老鼠'的？
How do you know Mouss?
他帮我带孩子
He babysits my kid.
好吧 跟着我
Okay, follow me.
- 你有带你的照片？- 有
- You got the photos on you? - Yeah.
- 多少 - 一千五
- How much? - $1,500.
如果再让我看见你 挖掉你的眼珠
If I ever see your face again, you're gonna lose an eye.
是很笨 我从自行车上摔下
Yeah, it was stupid. I fell off the bike.
你说的是 一直停在我们车库两年的自行车？
You mean the bike that's been in our garage for two years?
向后仰
Put your head back.
有人开拉娜的玩笑
Some guy made a crack about Lara.
所以 这就是你现在的作法？揍每个认为她有罪的人？
So that's what you do now? You punch everybody who thinks she's guilty?
你是什么意思？
What's that supposed to mean?
我是说重要的是你怎么想
It means it's important what you believe,
- 不要去管别人… - 真的吗？
- not what somebody else... - Really?
- 你相信她吗 妈妈？ - 怎么你想开始吵架了？
- Do you believe, Mom? - Why are you trying to start a fight?
来吧 伙计 我们走吧 他的包包在哪里？
Come on, buddy. Let's go. Where's his bag?
- 你为什么要这样？ - 不为什么
- Why are you doing this? - No reason.
我只是愚蠢地认为 凡是爱她的人
I just stupidly thought that the people who loved her
都会相信她是清白的 我错了
would actually believe she's innocent. My mistake.
别说了！
Stop this!
去给奶奶一个吻
Go give Grandma a kiss.
走吧
Come on.
你的脸会痛吗？
Does your face hurt?
偶而
A little.
你有打回他？
Did you hit him back?
不 我… 我没有
No, I... I didn't.
没关系
That's okay.
好了吗 伙计？
Okay, buddy?
我找会做高科技身份证的人
I'm looking for someone who does high-end IDs.
护照 社会安全卡
Passports, social security cards.
给我滚开！
Get out of here.
是谁？
Yeah?
酒吧碰过 我知道你在找啥
I was at the bar. I know what you are looking for.
我是聋子 你这个白痴 我读唇语
I'm deaf, you idiot. I read your lips.
你需要什么？
What do you need?
护照 驾驶执照
Passports, driver's license,
能过信用检查的社会安全号码
a social security number that'll take a credit check.
三千七
$3,700.
这太过分了
That's too much.
没有 你别想拿到手
It is if you never get them.
我需要照片和先付1000美元
I need photos and $1,000 in advance.
- 我星期三把他们带来 - 嘿 别来这里
- I'll bring them Wednesday. - Hey, not here.
我不希望你再回到这里来
I don't want you coming back here again.
唐氏停车场 在埃克特街 桥下 两点
Parking lot of Don's. Eckert Street. Under the bridge, 2:00.
如果我没准时到 快走
If I'm not there on time, leave.
在这里按指印
Put your thumb right there.
- 谢谢 这样就好了 - 谢谢您！
- Thanks. That's all I need. - Thank you.
我只需要几分钟
I'll just be a few moments.
戴眼镜？
Glasses?
是啊
Yes.
是啊 我发现自己改考卷改到睡着
Yeah, I found myself falling asleep grading papers.
多久了？
When?
我想大约一年前
I guess about a year ago.
一年前
A year ago.
看看你 怎么能把自己搞成这样？
Look at you. How can you do this to yourself?
妻子不在身边 我感到绝望
I am hopeless without my wife.
我甚至不能骑自行车
I can't even ride a bike.
对不起 房子卖了
Sorry about the house.
我以后不能想像你在那里了
I won't know where to picture you.
本来我闭上眼睛就能看到卢克在他的卧室 你在窗边沙发上
I close my eyes, I see Luke in his bedroom, and you on the sofa by the window.
我以后不能想像你在那里了
I won't know where to picture you anymore.
告诉我哪里去弄子弹
Show me where the bullets go.
嗨 我是约翰
Hi, it's John.
卢克今天不舒服
Luke's not feeling too well.
所以我要去接他 带他回家 好吗？
So I'm gonna pick him up and take him home, okay?
请卡尔代我三点的课
I need Carl to cover my 3:00 class.
谢谢
Thanks.
你倒底要不要接你该死的电话？
You ever gonna answer your goddamn phone?
你早该离开了
You were supposed to leave.
我需要证件
I need them.
你没注意到那家伙是个警察？
You notice that guy was a cop?
快把钱给我
Just give me the money.
你太心急了
You want this too much.
你会他妈的搞砸
You're gonna fuck it up.
嘿 布伦南先生
Hey, Mr. Brennan.
今天我要告诉你如何制造一把万能钥匙
Today I'm gonna show you how to make a key that can open any lock.
这就是所谓的“敲击”钥匙
It's called a bump key.
首先你要找到一把钥匙
First thing you need to do is you need to find a key
可以放入你试图打开的锁就行
that can fit into the type of lock that you're trying to open.
这里 我有一把可以放入大门的
Here I have a key that fits into my front door,
但我已换了锁 所以它打不开
but I just changed the locks, so it won't open.
首先找一把适合的钥匙
First thing you need to do is secure your key,
拿支铁锉刀来磨 像这样锉出棱角来
take a metal file and go through and start taking those mountains and valleys
有些地方要锉得深一点
all the way down to the lowest possible setting on the key.
“敲击”钥匙的重点在于 撞击瞬间的掌握
The bump key works by momentarily bumping those pins up,
因此 抓对那个瞬间
so that for a split second,
锁孔内的珠针会弹开 钥匙就能转开锁
the chamber is cleared of pins and thus, able to turn and open.
- 给你 - 请勿触摸
- Here you go. - Don't touch that.
- 抱歉 - 想抢我的工作？
- Sorry. - Trying to do my job?
那么 你在影片中哪里？
So you are where in here?
我在这里中间
I'm in the middle there.
在中间 你能指出自己吗？
In the middle. Can you point to yourself?
这就是我
That's me.
那
There.
所以靠近电梯的不是你
So that's not you back there by the elevators.
不 不 我是在这里的某个地方
No, no, I was around here somewhere.
你要老实告诉我吗？
You wanna tell me what's going on?
告诉你什么？
You want me to tell you?
是啊
Yes.
你知道什么是“敲击”钥匙吗？
Do you know what a bump key is?
什么？
Sorry?
如果这是你
If this was you,
你应该考虑到你孩子的未来
you might wanna think about what's gonna happen to your kids
如果他的父母都被关进牢里的话
if both their parents end up in prison.
爸爸
Dad?
Dad!
来了 伙计
Yeah, bud.
嗯
Yeah.
谢谢
Thanks.
因此 我们逮捕了他的妻子 现在我们控告他呕吐?
So we arrested his wife, and now we're gonna charge the man with vomiting.
他想卖房子 或者 有人要跟他买
He's selling the house. Or he has a buyer.
在这种景气？幸运的人
In this market? Lucky man.
我们现在可以去做警察的工作了吗？
Can we possibly go do police work now?
我现在知道你为什么这么久没结婚了
I don't know how you managed to stay single this long.
爸爸 我能吃饼干吗？
Dad, can I have my cookies?
- 你饿了吗？要吃个三明治？ - 不会
- You hungry? You want a sandwich? - No.
- 给你 - 谢谢
- There you go. - Thanks.
嘉莉！
Carrie!
我很抱歉 她刚刚才懂点事
I'm sorry. She's just already got it all figured out.
我是妮可
Nicole.
- 我记得 - 真的吗？
- I remember. - Really?
我记得你的女儿
I remember your daughter.
嗯 她很难忘记
Well, she's hard to forget.
卢克应该有拿这个回家
Luke was supposed to bring this home.
他跟他爸一样记性差
He has his father's memory.
这是嘉莉的生日聚会 来参加吧 我很想见见你的妻子
It's for Carrie's birthday party. Please, come. I'd love to meet your wife.
她不会去
She won't be there.
说来话长
It's complicated.
我明白了 和我有关
I understand. With me, too.
嘉莉 来吧 我们走吧
Carrie, come on, let's go.
我们要去吃点东西 你们要去吗？
We're gonna grab a bite to eat. Would you like to come?
- 不 我不…我们… - 有事要忙？
- No, I don't... We're kind of... - Busy?
来吧 我们欠你饼干
Come on. We owe you for the cookies.
嗯 这是事实
Well, that's true.
我自己也做饼干
And I did make those cookies myself.
还学着如何先包好
And learned how to pre-package them.
来吧 卢克
Come on, Luke.
所以 你都会找时间陪卢克？
So, do you trade off time with Luke?
不 卢克和我整天在一起
No, Luke and I are together full-time.
哇 难怪为什么我常常看到你
Wow. I guess that's why I see you so much.
她认为 陪他一起来这最好
She'd like nothing better than to be here, with him.
拉娜 她…她想念这一切
Lara, she... She misses all this.
我想是因为她比较先顾工作 是不是？
I guess it's all about priorities, isn't it?
不 她不是这样的
No, she's not like that.
她在监狱里
She's in prison.
- 我没跟什么人说 - 我明白了
- I don't tell most people. - I understand.
她是清白的 她没有杀那个女人
She's innocent. She didn't kill that woman.
好 我的意思是…
Good. I mean...
我敢肯定她没有
I'm sure she didn't.
我们真的该回家了
We really should be going home.
好
Okay.
非常感谢您的邀请 我们尽可能到
Thank you very much for the invitation. We'll try and make it.
那就太好了
That would be great.
- 再见 卢克！ - 再见
- Goodbye. Luke! - Bye.
来吧
Come on.
嘉莉 走吧！
Carrie, come on!
嘿  嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
怎么了?
What's wrong?
这是什么？
What is it?
不
No.
他们不能没先通知就要你移监
They can't move you without notice.
只三天不算先通知了
Three days isn't notice.
我只是在这里提上诉 我们早知道要去另一个监狱
I was only here through the appeal. We knew I was going to a prison.
不 不 我没有两个星期 我明天就要停止代管契约
No, no, I don't have two weeks. I gotta close the escrow tomorrow.
可是 你的名字甚至还没有拿下来呢 就没有办法让我…
Well, the title hasn't even been cleared yet. I mean, there's no way I can...
他们可以给我多少钱？
How much can they give me?
一毛都没
Nothing!
你们怎么跑来了？
What are you doing here?
我有课
I've got class.
你要乖 好吗？
You be good, okay?
谢谢
Thanks.
你没事吧？你们好吗？
Are you okay? You're okay?
- 你没事吧？ - 你在干什么？
- Are you okay? - What are you doing?
你几乎撞死我们！
You almost killed us!
我非常 非常抱歉
I'm so, so sorry.
你真的疯了 看也没看
You're out of your mind. You don't look.
走开 离我们远点！
Get away. Get away from us!
嘿
Hey.
怎么回事?
What's wrong?
没事
Nothing.
是卢克吗？
Is it Luke?
- 不是 - 那是什么？
- No. - What?
我…我问过梅耶
I... I asked Meyer
设法中止你转移监狱
to look into not having you moved.
我告诉他说 长距离旅行对我们有困难
I told him that traveling that distance would be a hardship on us,
卢克在学校已经有问题了 这是真的
that Luke was already having problems at school, which is true.
我没有足够的时间陪他
I haven't been spending enough time with him.
你没有？
You haven't?
真的
No.
你有没有？
You haven't?
老天 约翰
Jesus, John.
你已经做太多了
You really are too much.
卢克是过得不好 但那是因为妈妈是个杀人犯
Luke is having a hard time, because Mommy's in jail for murder,
不是因为爸爸没有花足够的时间陪他
not because Daddy doesn't spend enough time with him.
你父亲是对的 你真的不是和我们生活在同一个世界
Your father was right. You really don't live in the same world we do.
很好 你们还说得上话
That's nice, that the two of you talk.
我住在什么样的世界中 拉娜？
What world do I live in, Lara?
嗯 我不知道 约翰 但它不是真实的
Well, I don't know, John, but it's not the real one.
在其中的一个我将在这度过余生
The one in which I'm in here for the rest of my life.
所以不要跟我那样说话 幻想还能有幸福快乐的日子…
So don't be talking to me about fantasies like there's some happily ever...
安分点 好吗？
We good here?
是的 抱歉
Yes. Sorry.
现在 你要坐在这垮着脸 像是你让我失望了
Now you're gonna sit here all long-faced, like you let me down.
我的意思是 你要我怎么做？
I mean, what do you want me to do here?
你要我怎么做让你感觉好点？
You want me to make you feel better?
了解
Got it.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
现在你道歉了
Now you're apologizing.
你真的是个活宝
You really are a gem.
- 你要我怎么做 拉娜？ - 我要你怎么做？什么也不用
- What do you want from me, Lara? - What do I want from you? Nothing.
你已经太完美
You're already too perfect.
你甚至从来不问我 是不是我做的
You know, you never even asked me if I did it.
- 人是不是我杀的… - 因为我知道你没有
- If I killed her. - Because I know you didn't.
嗯 那你就错了
Well, then you'd be wrong.
是我做的
I'm done.
先生 你不能站在那儿
Sir, you can't stand there.
先生 请你立刻离开大楼
Sir, I need you to leave the building now.
先生？
Sir?
- 怎么了？ - 闭嘴
- What? - Shut up.
我不在乎你说什么或你怎么说
I don't care what you say or how you say it.
我不相信是你做的
I don't believe you did it.
永远不相信
And I never will.
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
而我向你保证
And I promise you
你不会在此过余生
this will not be your life.
停止
Shut up!
- 我不知道发生了什么事情 - 你做了什么？
- I don't know what's going on, man. - You done?
每个人都出去了
Everybody is out.
我要回去吉米那
I gotta get back to Jimmy.
后退！后退！
Back away! Back away!
放下枪！放下！
Drop the gun! Drop it!
先把狗带开了！
Put the dog away!
你敢射狗 我就杀了你！
You shoot the dog, I'll kill you!
- 你希望警察听到 混蛋？ - 好主意！
- You want the police here, asshole? - Good idea!
进屋里 进去 进去！
Get in, get in, get in!
- 你呢！ - 我不要进去那里！
- You, too! - I'm not getting in there!
进到里面去！
Get in there!
进去！进去！进去！
Get in! Get in! Get in!
好了 上锁 锁门
All right, lock it. Lock the door.
- 移动 - 你死定了
- Move! - You are dead.
- 我没有做任何事情 - 是你带他来这里！
- I didn't do anything. - You brought him here!
我没带他！
I didn't bring him!
跪下！给我跪下！
On your knees! On the floor!
好了 你的钱在哪？
All right. Where's your money?
在这里 拿了钱快滚
Here. It's worth it to get rid of you.
- 其他的在哪里？ - 给你
- Where's the rest? - Here.
- 多拿些 - 你把钱藏在哪里？
- Take more. - Where do you keep your money?
要我把我的钱都给你
I'm gonna give my money to you. Yeah.
- 我会开枪打死你 - 你甚至不敢杀狗
- I'll shoot you. - You can't even shoot a dog.
- 我会杀了你！ - 不 我要杀了你们！
- I'll kill you both! - No, I'm gonna kill you both!
- 快把钱给他！ - 死婊子闭上嘴！
- Just give him your money! - Keep your dead bitch mouth shut!
把你的钱给他！
Give him your money!
老天！
Jesus!
懂了吗？你是不会杀了我的
See? You ain't gonna kill me.
你只是装模作样而已
This is the worst you could do?
回家去等我 我会找到你 我会杀了你
Go home. I'll come, I'll find you and I'll kill you.
你浪费了一些好东西！
You're wasting some good shit there!
是啊 好东西
Yeah, good shit.
高度浓度的酒精
High alcohol content.
你打算怎么办？你要烧死我？
What are you gonna do? You gonna burn me out?
是啊 这就是我要做的
Yeah. That's what I'm gonna do.
耶稣基督！
Jesus Christ!
这是一个冰毒实验室 你这白痴！
This is a meth lab, you idiot!
不
No.
会爆炸…
It was.
告诉我！你的钱在哪？
Tell me! Where's your money?
我的孩子在楼上！
My kid is upstairs!
- 起来！ - 老天！
- Get up! - Jesus!
起来！
Get up!
拜托
Please.
请放我走 求你
Please, let me go, please.
有人在吗？
Anybody here?
不要把我留在这里
Don't leave me here.
我不希望死在这
I don't wanna die here.
拜托！
Please!
请送我去医院！
Please, get me to a hospital!
我不能呼吸
I can't breathe.
拜托
Please.
我不能呼吸
I can't breathe.
我不能…我不能…
I can't... I can't...
快让开
Get out of my way.
- 找到些什么？ - 该死的奇蹟
- What do we have? - A freaking miracle.
地下室冰毒场失火 房子仍然屹立不倒
Meth lab in the basement, the house still standing.
应该变成火山爆发才对
Should be just a crater.
我们认识他吗？
We know him?
亚历·盖达尔 有暴力和贩毒前科
Alex Gaidar, history of violence and drug trafficking.
他有孩子吗？
He have a kid?
邻居说 妻子去年带他离开了
Neighbor said wife left with him last year.
大惊喜
Big surprise there.
有血迹
And this blood,
都查过血型了吗？
they type it all yet?
没有 但有人流着血从后门离开
No, but someone left through the back door bleeding.
三区发现一名受枪伤的受害者死在捷运的长椅上
Zone Three found a gunshot victim dead on a transit bench.
嘿
Hey.
我来接卢克
I've just come to pick up Luke.
他睡着了
He's sound asleep.
是啊 我只是来接卢克
Yeah, I've just come to get Luke.
约翰
John.
你没事吧？
Are you all right?
是啊 我很好
Yeah. I'm fine.
嘿 伙计
Hey, buddy.
醒醒吧小子 我们要回家了
Wake up, bud, we're going home.
所以 你要说什么？
So, what do you say?
谢谢你 奶奶
Thank you, Grandma.
我想你应该给奶奶一个热吻
I think you should give Grandma a big kiss.
- 我不想再亲人了 - 小子
- I'm too tired for kisses. - Buddy.
这没关系 我下周末会有大量的吻
That's okay. I'll get lots of kisses next weekend.
我们要带他去库茨敦参加秋季节…
We want to take him to the Fall Festival in Kutztown
可以骑小马喔
where the Clydesdales are.
- 再见 - 再见
- See you. - Bye.
再见
Bye.
嘿
Hey.
- 再见 爷爷 - 再见
- Bye, Grandpa. - Bye.
再见
Goodbye.
再见 妈妈
Bye, Mom.
再见
Bye.
你这年纪还会多愁善感
You're getting sentimental in your old age.
我是
Yeah.
嗯 还不如喝点咖啡
Well, might as well have some coffee.
呦！白痴！
Yo! Idiots!
我可以带着他？
Can I carry him?
不 小子 只拿袋子能装的 好吗？
No, bud. Only what fits in the bag, all right?
那我放口袋里？
What about my pockets?
可以放口袋里
Or your pockets.
哈罗
Hello?
伙计？我会马上回来 好吗？
Bud? I'll be back in a moment, okay?
好
Okay.
嘿 老兄
Hey, bud.
那么…
So...
你没事吧？
You all right?
嗯
Yeah.
我们去参加庆生会
They're calling all the party animals.
耶塔街922号
922 Yetta Street.
我知道在哪里
I know where that is.
好吗？我们出发
Okay? Here we go.
是的 尾灯符合任何2004至2009年的普锐斯
Yeah, taillight matches any 2004 to 2009 Prius.
什么样的罪犯会开普锐斯？
What kind of criminal drives a Prius?
一个对社会负责任的
A socially responsible one.
全城有超过 1000名车主登记 全州有7000
There's over 1 ,000 registered in the city, 7,000 in the state.
- 有多少人是有案的罪犯？ - 整个州六个
- How many are registered to felons? - Six in the state.
四个贪污 白领犯罪 一个强奸犯 一个杀人犯
Four to embezzlers, white-collar criminals, one to a rapist, one to a murderer.
- 从杀人犯开始 - 她在监狱里
- Start with the murderer. - She's in prison for life.
强奸犯出狱了
Rapist is out.
找到他
Find him.
来吧
Come on.
- 哈罗  - 嗨
- Hello. - Hi.
- 很高兴见到你 - 我也很高兴见到你
- Good to see you. - It's good to see you, too.
- 你好 卢克 - 这是一个小马
- Hi, Luke. - It's a pony.
喔包装真精致
Those aren't easy to wrap.
你知道派对11:00结束 对不对？
You know the party is not until 11 :00, right?
真的吗？
Really?
现在几点？九点左右？我很抱歉 我应该看清楚请帖
What is it? Around 9:00? I'm sorry. I should've read it more carefully.
没问题 你为什么不拿这个去给嘉莉？
It's no problem. Why don't you go give this to Carrie?
嗯 我猜你可以提帮帮我
Well, I guess you can help.
其实 我得走了 几个地方要跑
Actually, I've gotta go and run some errands.
很抱歉
Sorry.
那我们再见了
We'll see you later then.
非常感谢
Thanks so much.
他有我父母的电话号码
He has my parents' phone number.
在他的外套 最上面口袋里
In his jacket. Top pocket of his jacket.
如果我迟到了
If I'm running late.
没问题
No problem.
该名疑犯现在坐轮椅了 不知道这是报应 或只是运气不好
The rapist is in a wheelchair. Not sure if that was karma orjust bad luck.
那个杀人犯 她被关押在哪里？
The murderer. Where is she incarcerated?
县立监狱 就在本地
County, right here in town.
她有丈夫或一个已经长大了会开车的孩子吗？
Does she have a husband or a kid old enough to drive?
是吗？什么？
Yes? What?
拉娜 布伦南的血液报告不妙
Lara Brennan's blood work.
打给实验室
Get the lab.
你惹毛了某人 这是肯定的
You pissed somebody off, that's for sure.
- 仍然忙线 我会继续试 - 不 叫救护车
- It's still busy. I'll keep trying. - No. Get an ambulance.
带她到大学医院 我会在那里见他们
Take her to University Hospital. I'll meet them there.
好 谢谢
Right. Thanks.
她丈夫 是教师
Husband, schoolteacher.
你有她家的地址吗？
You got a home address?
没有车在车库 你想申请搜查令？
No car in the garage. You want to get a warrant?
嗯
Yeah.
去申请搜查
Get the warrant.
拉娜 布伦南被转移到大学医院
Lara Brennan's being transferred to University Hospital.
- 现在？- 现在
- Right now? - Right now.
去打电话给护送车辆
Have them call the escort vehicle.
告诉他们我们10分钟内在医院会合
Tell them we'll meet them at the hospital in less than 10.
是啊 是啊 我们在这里 囚犯很安全 没有问题
Yeah. Yeah, we're here. Prisoner's secure. No problems.
好的
Will do.
把双手举高
Hands where I can see 'em.
约翰？
John?
和手机
And the phone.
你在这里做什么 约翰？
What are you doing here, John?
把你的手放在头上
Put your hands on your head.
约翰 你在干什么？
John, what are you doing?
解开她 跪下去
Uncuff her. Kneel down.
约翰 停止这一切
John, stop this.
跪下去 面对墙壁
Kneel down. Face the wall.
单位 2242 安全
Unit 2242 secure.
- 她刚才是说… - 开灯鸣笛！
- She just said... - Just take the light.
手和脚 绑越紧越好
Hands and feet, pull 'em as tight as you can.
你要是跟他走出那门 你们都会死
You walk out that door with him, you will both be dead.
- 闭嘴 - 约翰 他是对的
- Shut up. - John, he's right.
听他的 你会害死我们的
Listen to him. You're gonna get us killed.
- 你为什么要这样做？ - 因为我们没有别的选择！
- Why are you doing this? - Because we have no other choice!
- 把他穿上 - 不 这不是真的！
- Put 'em on. - No. That's not true!
- 把衣服穿上 拉娜 - 不要
- Put the clothes on, Lara. - No.
- 现在！  - 不！
- Now! - No!
好
Okay.
打给你的儿子 告诉他你不来了
You call your son and tell him you're not coming.
- 他在哪里 - 他在等待着你
- Where is he? - He's waiting for you.
你要告诉他你不来？
You wanna tell him you're not coming?
- 你怎么能这样对我？ - 按下“发送”
- How can you do this to me? - Push "send."
告诉他我也不回去了
Tell him I'm not coming, either.
- 约翰 - 我们到底要不要回家 拉娜？
- John. - Does it look like I'm going home, Lara?
你打电话 告诉他现在他是孤儿了
You call him, tell him he's alone now
而且他的妈妈和爸爸都不会再回来了
and his mom and dad are not coming back.
老天 约翰
Jesus, John.
你这个混球
You son of a bitch.
我是李夫森医生 有一个病人从县立监狱转到这里
I'm Dr. Lifson. You've got a patient here from County Jail.
拉娜布伦南？
Lara Brennan?
是的 我们上了D50点滴 20个单位的胰岛素
Yes, we started an IV. D50 with 20 units of insulin.
收到
Copy.
保安！
Security!
出去！出去！
Out! Out!
- 喂！喂！ - 后退！
- Hey, hey. - Back away!
- 别做傻事 - 你别过来！
- Now don't be stupid. - You stay back!
我们每一个出口都有人 约翰 你们会被当场击毙
We have units at every exit, John. You will be shot trying to leave.
快按按钮 拉娜
Hit the button, Lara.
- 停止 - 按按钮！
- Stop. - Hit the button!
约翰 你不能这样做
John, do not do this.
- 楼梯在哪里？ - 那边
- Where are the stairs? - There.
男性和女性 白色的实验室外衣 停车场
Male and female, white lab coats, parking levels.
嘿 会顺利的
Hey. It's gonna be okay.
看着我 看着我 一切都没问题
Look at me, look at me. Everything's gonna be okay.
照我说的去做 一切都会好起来的
Just do what I say when I say it. Everything will be okay.
拉娜 脱掉外衣
Lara, take the coat off.
来吧
Come on.
没关系 你留在这儿
It's okay. You stay here.
所有保安人员…
All security personnel...
- 守住门！ - 是
- Watch the door! - Yeah.
停止.
Stop.
可恶..
Shit.
谁在大厅？
Who's in the lobby?
嘿 听着 有谁在大厅？
Hey, listen. Is anybody in the lobby?
不要看
Don't look.
跑!
Run!
很好
Great!
回来！
Back here!
让开
Move.
动作快点！
Let's get moving!
来吧
Come on.
这里!
Here!
喂！喂！
Hey, hey!
拯救企鹅！
Go Penguins!
放下你的头发
Let your hair down.
哈里斯 那边 走！
Harris, that way. Go!
嘿
Hey!
哈里斯 他们在地铁 哈里斯！地铁！
Harris, they're in the subway. Harris! The subway!
收到
Got it.
他们在月台上！
They're on the platform!
封锁车站每个出口！
Block stations in either directions!
呼叫铁路局 停止所有的列车！
Call the Port Authority. Stop all the trains!
等 等等…
Wait, wait, wait.
我们在做什么？
What are we doing?
列车门要关了
Stand clear of the closing doors, please.
让开！匹兹堡警局！
Move! Pittsburgh PD!
四号轨道的列车 我要它停止 停止那列车！
The train on track four, I want it stopped. Stop that train!
下一站…
Next stop...
抱紧我
Hold on to me.
嘿 孩子 两只手
Hey, kid, two hands.
不 不
No. No.
这里
This way.
那边
There.
- 红灯 - 坐稳了
- Red light. - Hold on.
红灯！
Red light!
打给市长 关闭巴士和火车站
Ring the city. Close bus and train stations.
把他们的描述传给州的警察
And get their description to the state police.
收到
Copy that.
- 他们该死的孩子几岁？ - 六岁
- How old is their damn kid? - Six.
找出他在哪里
Find out where he is.
- 你为什么不先告诉我？ - 你会阻止我
- Why didn't you tell me? - You would've stopped me.
你的胰岛素在这里
Your insulin is in here.
那有个化妆包 有刷子 乳液 化妆品
There's a case in here. It's got a brush, moisturizer, makeup.
我一向搞不太懂 希望我没拿错
Everything you had was old. I hope I got it right.
你还记得在哪最后一次见到他吗？
You remember where you last saw him?
你想猜猜谁刚刚逃出了监狱？
You want to take a guess who just escaped from jail?
等一下
Hold on a second.
- 哈罗  - 嗨 我是来接我的儿子
- Hello. - Hi. I'm here to pick up my son.
他们还没有回来
They aren't back yet.
他们去哪？
Back from where?
动物园
From the zoo.
本来就是动物园派对啊
It's a zoo party.
他们应该一个小时后回来 如果你想等
They should be back in about an hour if you'd like to wait.
不 谢谢
No. Thank you.
这是怎么回事？怎么了？
What's wrong? What is it?
- 他在哪儿？卢克在哪？ - 他在派对
- Where is he? Where's Luke? - He's at the party.
什么派对？你说在这里聚会
What party? You said the party was here.
我错了 她是要带他们到动物园
I was wrong. She's taken them to the zoo.
- 目的地 匹兹堡动物园 - 她 ?
- Destination, Pittsburgh Zoo. - She?
预计抵达时间 17分钟
Estimated drive time, 17 minutes.
嘉莉的母亲 妮可
Carrie's mother, Nicole.
检查邻居！
Check the neighbors!
问有关男孩以及过去数天有何异常
We're looking for the boy and anything they've noticed in the last few days.
到达时间 11分钟
Time to destination, 11 minutes.
前方1,000英尺 靠左
In 1 ,000 feet, bear left.
前方500英尺 靠左
In 500 feet, bear left.
前方100英尺 靠左
In 100 feet, bear left.
靠左
Bear left.
你转错了
You took the wrong turn.
约翰 动物园在我们背后 你转错了
John, the zoo's behind us. You took the wrong turn.
宝贝 你在干什么？
Babe, what are you doing?
她会打电话给我的父母
She'll call my parents.
- 什么？ - 他们会照顾他
- What? - They'll look after him,
我会想出办法 去接到他的
and I'll figure out a way of getting him to us.
你是不是疯了？
Are you out of your mind?
我算过！时间上来不及！
I tried! There's no more time!
现在随时 都可能有一个路障摆在我们面前
Any second now, there's gonna be a roadblock ahead of us.
警方开始动了！如果我们现在不出去 我们出不去！
It might be there now! If we don't get out now, we don't get out!
我会想到办法 再回去接他 好吗？我会找到办法的
I'll find a way of getting him to us, all right? I'll find a way.
帮我照顾他 我不知道怎么感谢你才好
不 真的 没事的
No, really, it's fine. I just can't thank you enough for taking care of him.
嘿 这是我们的荣幸
Hey, it was our pleasure.
嗨
Hi.
我也坐后面 好吗？
I'm going to sit back here, okay?
当然…
Sure.
各个收费站前都大排长龙
The traffic is backing up at the toll plazas.
市中心更糟 因警方封锁了火车站…
It's worse downtown where police have cordoned off the train station
并搜索所有乘客
and are searching all passengers.
西尔维亚帕特森 在联合车站为您报导…
Joining us from Union Station, our very own Sylvia Patterson.
约翰？
John?
我们要怎么办？
What are we gonna do?
我们要到火车站
We're going to the train station.
- 留在车内 好吧
- Stay in the car. - Okay.
长官 对不起市长被耽搁了
Sir, I'm sorry the mayor was delayed,
但我并没下令停止所有车辆
but I did not tell them to stop every vehicle.
只是针对那些夫妇带着一个孩子的
Just the ones with a couple and a child.
长官 我知道我的…
Sir, I know my...
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
你确定20美元就够了吗？火车票要60块耶
Are you sure $20 is enough? Ticket to Buffalo costs three times that.
是啊 反正我们顺路嘛
Yeah. We're going that way anyway.
加大部属 发送他们的照片到每个火车站
Go wider. Send their photos to every train,
公车站和机场 在300英里半径内的
bus station and airport in a 300-mile radius.
因此 俄亥俄 马里兰 西弗吉尼亚
So Ohio, Maryland, West Virginia,
纽约 新泽西 弗吉尼亚 密歇根 肯塔基和印第安纳州？
New York, New Jersey, Virginia, Michigan, Kentucky and Indiana?
你了不起 你知道他们往哪个方向走？
You know what direction they're going in, smart-ass?
- 再见了 汤姆 - 再次感谢您
- See you again, Tom. - Thanks again.
你想看看吗？
You want to see it?
看看它会告诉我他们在哪里吗
Only if it will tell me where they are.
没有那么幸运
Not so lucky.
对不起 你有叫咖啡吗？
Excuse me. Do you call this coffee?
在安大略省和魁北克省有多少机场？
How many airports in Ontario and Quebec?
你要我停下来开始算？
You want me to stop calling and count?
- 去这么远 只带随身行李 - 对不起?
- Long way to go with just a carry-on. - I'm sorry?
你要去这么远 只带随身行李？
Long way to go with just a carry-on.
你知道有多少次你们机场弄丢我的行李吗？
You know how many times you guys have lost our bags?
这是你的机票和登机牌
Here's your tickets and boarding passes.
感谢你
Thank you.
他们找到了他父母
They found the parents.
你们决定去坐车闲晃一整天吗？
You decided to go for a drive for the entire day?
乔治想去看看森林
George wanted to see the leaves.
而你真的不知道他们要去哪里 对不对？
And you have absolutely no idea where they're going, right?
我说过 我跟他从来说不上话
I told you. We never spoke.
嘿
Hey.
我能够做到
I'll do this.
来吧 卢克
Go ahead, Luke.
哈罗
Hello.
你看起来像是需要喝一杯
You look like you need to get away.
感谢你
Thank you.
来吧 伙计
Come on, buddy.
- 可惜你没有找到更多的了 - 是啊
- Too bad you didn't find more of it. - Yeah.
真希望能知道这是哪
And I wish I could figure out where this is.
我还上网比对能想到的每一个旅游目的地
I checked Web sites for every tourist destination I could think of.
- 这是海地总统府 - 什么？
- That's the Presidential Palace. - What?
电视新闻说它在地震中倒塌
It was all over CNN when it collapsed during the earthquake.
我们知道他们要去哪里！
We know where they're going!
给我看看
Show me.
谢谢您久等了 我们马上就要开始登机
Thank you for waiting. We'll soon begin boarding by rows.
在登机口拦下大家 看看这个
Hold them at the gate. Take a look.
出发
Let's go!
对不起 大家 暂停登机
Excuse me, folks. No one else on.
对不起 大家 对不起 对不起 请
Excuse me, folks. Excuse me. Excuse me, please.
抱歉 这个航班没有人符合描述
Sorry. There's no one by that description on this flight.
不 他们在上面
No. They're on it.
你有照片吗？
Do you have the photographs?
我们有照片 他们不在这架飞机上
We have the photographs. They're not on this plane.
今晚是否有任何其他航班前往海地？
Are there any other flights to Haiti tonight?
没有其他航班 还有别的事吗？
No other flights. Anything else?
没有了 谢谢
No. No. Thank you.
下起雨来了
It's starting to rain.
我打电话给联邦调查局
I'll call the FBI.
你有想过吗 为什么我们只找到这袋 而没找到其他的？
You ever ask yourself why we found this bag and not the others?
机长已关闭了安全带指示灯
The captain has switched off the seat belt light.
飞行到加拉加斯 委内瑞拉 航程约五个小时 32分钟
Flight time to Caracas, Venezuela, this evening is five hours and 32 minutes.
请您就座 机长要求你系上安全带
While in your seat, the captain asks that you keep your seat belt fastened.
这家伙是个老师吗？
This guy's a teacher?
在社区大学
At a community college.
嘿！
Hey!
- 她听到一个钮扣弹出 - 什么？
- She heard a button pop. - What?
她听到一个钮扣掉了
She heard a button pop.
我们搜查现场的时候在下雨吗？
Was it raining when we searched the scene?
三年前？
Three years ago?
我们在这里干什么？
What are we doing here?
拜托像个警察 抓另一头
Why don't you act like a cop? Grab the other side.
你真的是疯了
You're out of your mind.
- 抬起来 - 好了
- Ready? - Yeah.
- 扶好 - 恩 恩
You got it?
你真的以为你会找到它？
You really thought you were gonna find it?